A Guide to the Papers of Chalmers Laughlin Gemmill 1914-(1960-1975)-1997
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
The Papers of Chalmers Laughlin Gemmill 1914-(1960-1975)-1997
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-23
The collection consists of 3 record boxes and 5 Hollinger boxes of processed materials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Daphne Gemmill. The "Publications Department of Pharmacology, University of Virginia School of Medicine" 1947-1953 was given by the Department.
Biographical/Historical Information
Chalmers Laughlin Gemmill was born in Cresson Pennsylvania on November 24, 1901. He graduated with a degree in chemistry from Lafayette College in 1914, and received his M.D. from Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine in 1926. He worked for a while in the Johns Hopkins Department of Physiology, and also did post-graduate research at three institutions overseas: the Kaiser Wilhelm Institute in Heidelberg, Germany; Lund University in Lund, Sweden; and Cambridge University in Cambridge, England. He married Vivienne Angeline Warry on January 10, 1938, and had one child, Daphne.
In 1941, Dr. Gemmill became an instructor at the Navy's new research center for Aviation Medicine in Pensacola, Florida. He rose to the rank of Captain (MC), and was discharged in 1945, when he joined the faculty of the University of Virginia Medical School as a professor in the Department of Pharmacology, a position he held until he retired in 1972. He was Chair of the Department from 1949-1967. While at UVA, he conducted extensive research on a variety of subjects, and was given a grant to do research on the history of medicine, specifically a study of silphium, at the Wellcome Library in London. Dr. Gemmill traveled extensively, and attended a number of the international symposia, keeping scrapbooks of many of his travels.
Dr. Gemmill retired from the Medical School Faculty in 1972 and died in June of 1982.
Scope and Content
The Chalmers Laughlin Gemmill Collection includes correspondence and materials related to his research in the history of medicine, including papers on the Charlottesville General Hospital during the Civil War, Robley Dunglison, and ancient pharmacology. The collection also contains scrapbooks from his post-graduate research overseas and his attendance at the International Physiological Congresses. A set of medals from the Congresses, along with other medals depicting the history of medicine are also included.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in chronological order by subject.
Contents List
- Series I: Personal Papers
  - Collection Donation Papers 1986, 1988 (Box-folder 01:01)
  - Commencement Program: Ivyland Borough School 1914 June 9 (Box-folder 01:02)
  - Class Day Program: William Penn Charter School 1918 June 5 (Box-folder 01:03)
  - Items regarding Danvers State Hospital 1924 July (Box-folder 01:04)
  - Graduation Program: Johns Hopkins University 1926 June 8 (Box-folder 01:05)
  - Boy Scout Camp Photo: Treasure Island Camp, Philadelphia 1927 (Box-folder 01:06)
  - Papers regarding Gemmill's Medical School scholarship 1927 June 15 (Box-folder 01:07)
  - Scrapbook 1925-1967 (Box-folder 01:08)
  - Scrapbook 1928 (Box-folder 01:09)
  - Scrapbook from Kaiser Wilhelm Institute 1931 (Box-folder 01:10)
  - Letter from Cambridge University regarding research 1934 March 16 (Box-folder 01:11)
  - Scrapbook from Cambridge 1934 (Box-folder 01:12)
  - Honorable Discharge from Home Defense Reserve 1919 May 7 (Box-folder 01:13)
  - Certificate of Completion of ROTC Infantry camp 1919 August 2 (Box-folder 01:14)
  - Photographs from Naval Air Training Base, Pensacola, Florida [1941] (Box-folder 01:15)
  - Pamphlet: "The Naval Air Training Bases, Pensacola, Florida, thru World War II" 1946 January (Box-folder 01:16)
  - Certificate of Satisfactory Service during WWII 1946 January 3 (Box-folder 01:17)
  - Certificate: Completion of Correspondence Course, Naval War College 1950 February 6 (Box-folder 01:18)
  - Appointment as Special Guest Lecturer at Naval Medical School n.d. (Box-folder 01:19)
  - American Physiological Society Anniversary Certificate 1938 (Box-folder 01:20)
  - Tile from Sairenji Temple 1951 September 1 (Box-folder 01:21)
  - Passport 1964 (Box-folder 01:22)
  - Photograph: Department of Pharmacology [1965] (Box-folder 01:23)
  - Letters regarding travel 1965 (Box-folder 01:24)
  - Membership letter: American Institute of the History of Pharmacy 1967 February 15 (Box-folder 01:25)
  - Letter from Emerson Venable to C.L. Gemmill, invitation to join American Institute of Chemists 1968 September 26 (Box-folder 01:26)
  - Two letters from daughter Daphne, newspaper photocopy 1967, 1972 (Box-folder 01:27)
  - Letter from daughter Daphne [Gemmill] to Kathy [Woodson] and other papers related to the artist, Brian Stonehouse, who made a portrait of Dr. Gemmill which is in the Artifacts collection. 1995-97, n.d. (Box-folder 01:28)
  - Navy Scrapbook, Pensacola, Florida 1941 (Box-folder 02:01)
  - Society of Medical Consultants Certificate 1978 (Box-folder 02:02)
- Series II: Physiological Congresses
  - Scrapbooks
    - Scrapbook for the 15th Physiological Congress in Leningrad, Russia 1935 (Box-folder 02:03)
    - Scrapbook for the 16th Physiological Congress in Zurich, Switzerland 1938 (Box-folder 02:04)
    - Scrapbook items for the 9th Industrial Medicine Congress in London, England 1948 (Box-folder 02:05)
    - Scrapbook for the 19th Physiological Congress in Montreal, Canada 1953 (Box-folder 02:06)
    - Scrapbook for the 20th Physiological Congress in Brussels, Belgium 1956 (Box-folder 02:07)
    - Scrapbook for the 21st Physiological Congress in Buenos Aires Argentina 1959 (Box-folder 02:08)
    - Scrapbook for the 22nd Physiological Congress in the Netherlands 1962 (Box-folder 02:09)
  - Medals
    - Commemorative Medal from International Physiological Congress VI, Brussels 1904 (Box-folder 03:01)
    - Commemorative Medal from International Physiological Congress XIII, Boston 1929 (Box-folder 03:02)
    - Commemorative Medal from International Physiological Congress XIV, Rome 1932 (Box-folder 03:03)
    - Commemorative Medal from International Physiological Congress XV, Leningrad-Moscow 1935 (Box-folder 03:04)
    - Commemorative Medal from International Physiological Congress XX, Brussels (x2) 1956 (Box-folder 03:05)
    - Commemorative Medal from International Physiological Congress XXIII, Tokyo 1965 (Box-folder 03:06)
- Series III: Medals
  - Letter from the Medical Heritage Society, re: medal subscription for "Medallic History of Medicine" 1969 October 28 (Box-folder 03:07)
  - Invoice for Medallic History of Medicine, Issues 53 and 54 1972 January 28 (Box-folder 03:08)
  - Aesculapius silver proof (in casing) and pamphlet 1969 November (Box-folder 03:09)
  - Pamphlets for coins in the Medallic History of Medicine set (60) 1969 - 1971 (Box-folder 03:10)
  - The Medallic History of Medicine 1972 (Box-folder 03:11)
  - Medallic History of Medicine - Medal Display book 1969 (Box-folder 03:12)
  - "Medallic History of Pharmacy" pamplet set 1970 - 1971 (Box-folder 03:13)
  - Medallic History of Pharmacy - Medal Display book 1970 (Box-folder 03:14)
  - 'Great Men of Medicine' Art Medal pamphlets: Addison to Louis n.d (Box-folder 03:15)
  - 'Great Men of Medicine' Art Medal pamphlets: Maimonides to Withering n.d. (Box-folder 03:16)
  - Great Men of Medicine - Medal Display book 1 of 2 n.d. (Box-folder 03:17)
  - Great Men of Medicine - Medal Display book 2 of 2 n.d. (Box-folder 03:18)
  - "Great Men of Science" commemorative medal - Alfred Nobel (large, with stand) 1972 (Box-folder 03:19)
  - "Great Men of Science" medal - Niels Bohr [1972] (Box-folder 03:20)
  - "Great Men of Science" medal - the Curies [1972] (Box-folder 03:21)
  - "Great Men of Science" medal - Euclid [1972] (Box-folder 03:22)
  - "Great Men of Science" medal - Galen [1972] (Box-folder 03:23)
  - "Great Men of Science" pamphlets (1-32), Dawin - Bohr 1972-1973 (Box-folder 03:24)
  - "Great Men of Science" pamphlets (34-74), Theophrastus - Kepler 1973-1975 (Box-folder 03:25)
  - "History of Surgery" medal - Albucasis [1971] (Box-folder 03:26)
  - "History of Surgery" medal - Egyptian Surgery [1971] (Box-folder 03:27)
  - "History of Surgery" pamphlets 1971-1974 (Box-folder 03:28)
- Series IV: Research Interests
  - Charlottesville General Hospital
    - Letters
      - Harry J Warthen to C.L. Gemmill, re: Civil War Centennial 1960 February 24 - 1961 September 8 (Box-folder 04:01)
      - Correspondence between Victor Gondos (Archivist at National Archives) and C.L. Gemmill, notes 1960 October 10 - November 21 (Box-folder 04:02)
      - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and Duke University Library Manuscript Department 1960 October 21 - 1963 June 20 (Box-folder 04:03)
      - Correspondence between H.H. Cunningham (Elon College) and C.L. Gemmill, photocopy 1960 October 24 - 1963 August 28 (Box-folder 04:04)
      - Letter from Mrs. Walter H. Page to C.L. Gemmill, re: Civil War hospitals 1960 November 25 (Box-folder 04:05)
      - Letter from W.L. Davenport to C.L. Gemmill, re: Civil War hospitals 1960 December 1 (Box-folder 04:06)
      - Letter from C.L. Gemmill to Mrs. S.J. Robinson, Jr. 1960 December 15 (Box-folder 04:07)
      - George B. Oliver (Randolph Macon College) to C.L. Gemmill, re: Civil War hospital exhibit 1961 February 3 (Box-folder 04:08)
      - C.L. Gemmill to Robert Chandler (Thalimer's Dept. Store), re: supplies for Civil War Hospital exhibit 1961 February 13 (Box-folder 04:09)
      - Correspondence between Thelma Vane Hoke and C.L. Gemmill, re: Medical School during Civil War 1961 February 14-20 (Box-folder 04:10)
      - Correspondence between AMA and C.L. Gemmill, re: School of Medicine during Civil War 1961 February 20 - March 3 (Box-folder 04:11)
      - Correspondence between Francis L. Berkeley (Manuscript Division, Alderman Library) and C.L. Gemmill 1961 March 8 - 21 (Box-folder 04:12)
      - Letter from Paul Saunier to C.L. Gemmill, re: Items for Civil War exhibit 1961 March 13 (Box-folder 04:13)
      - Correspondence between Bernard P. Chamberlain and C.L. Gemmill, re: Civil War Centennial, meeting report 1961 April 17 - 1963 July 29 (Box-folder 04:14)
      - Letter from A.W. von Struve to C.L. Gemmill, re: Charlottesville census records 1961 May 11 (Box-folder 04:15)
      - Letter from Anne Richards to C.L. Gemmill 1961 May 31 (Box-folder 04:16)
      - Letter from Anne Freudenberg (Assistand in Manuscripts, Alderman Library) to C.L. Gemmill 1961 June 1 (Box-folder 04:17)
      - Correspondence between William L. Dolley, Jr. and C.L. Gemmill 1961 June 4-6 (Box-folder 04:18)
      - Letters from Marie McKennie Pinck 1963 January 13 and n.d. (Box-folder 04:19)
      - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and James W. Patton (Director, Southern Historical Collection, UNC) 1963 May 29-30 (Box-folder 04:20)
      - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and L.M. Blackford 1963 June 13-26 (Box-folder 04:21)
      - Letter from Wilhelm Moll (Medical Librarian), re: Civil war letters, two enclosures 1964 January 21 (Box-folder 04:22)
    - Other items
      - "Hospitals in Charlottesville during the War Between the States" by Isabelle H. Goss 1942 July 8 (Box-folder 04:23)
      - 'The Tristate Medical Journal' containing an article by C.L. Gemmill 1961 April (Box-folder 04:24)
      - 'Draw Sheet' containing an article about the Civil War exhibit 1961 May 31 (Box-folder 04:25)
      - Medical Alumni Day Program, with Dr. Gemmill scheduled to speak during dinner 1961 June 2 (Box-folder 04:26)
      - Layout for exhibit on "Charlottesville General Hospital, 1861-1865" n.d. (Box-folder 04:27)
    - Manuscripts
      - "The Charlottesville General Hospital, 1861-1865" by C.L. Gemmill, MD n.d. (Box-folder 04:28)
      - "Documents relating to the Charlottesville General Hospital, 1861-1865" by Chalmers L. Gemmill n.d. (Box-folder 04:29)
  - Hippocratic Oath
    - Letters
      - Correspondence between Cecile Desbarats (McGill University) and C.L. Gemmill, re: medical oaths 1961 April 17-19 (Box-folder 04:30)
      - Letter to C.L. Gemmill from A.J. Dickson (Wellcome Historical Medical Library), re: Hippocratic oath 1961 April 28 (Box-folder 04:31)
      - Letter from Maurice Levine, re: Hippocratic oath 1961 April 28 (Box-folder 04:32)
      - Letter to C.L. Gemmill from John C. Krantz, Jr. (University of Maryland, School of Medicine), re: Hippocratic oath 1962 February 19 (Box-folder 04:33)
      - Letter to C.L. Gemmill from John Scarborough (University of Kentucky), re: Hippocratic oath 1970 September 20 (Box-folder 04:34)
    - Other items
      - Three Medical Oaths n.d. (Box-folder 04:35)
      - Physicians Plaques Order Form n.d. (Box-folder 04:36)
      - Hippocratic Oath in Alumni Bulletin 1966 August 10 (Box-folder 04:37)
      - "The Presages of divine Hippocrates...With the Protestation or Oath which Hippocrates caused his scholars to make" n.d. (Box-folder 04:38)
      - Medical Oaths n.d. (Box-folder 04:39)
      - Hippocratic Oath Cartoons n.d. (Box-folder 04:40)
      - "The Science Teacher's Creed" n.d. (Box-folder 04:41)
      - "The Order or Etiquette of Medicine" n.d. (Box-folder 04:42)
      - Hippocrates parody: Moliere's "Le Malade Imaginaire" (French with translations) n.d. (Box-folder 04:43)
      - Catalogue of the works of Claude Galien 1913 (Box-folder 04:44)
      - Catalogue of the works of Hippocrates 1921 (Box-folder 04:45)
      - Hippocratic Oath from Bulletin of the History of Medicine 1943 (Box-folder 04:46)
      - Updated Oath of Hippocrates (French) 1949 (Box-folder 04:47)
      - References on Medical Oaths from Armed Forces Medical Library 1955 March 3 (Box-folder 04:48)
      - "Principles of Medical Ethics" pamphlet published by American Medical Association (AMA) 1957 (Box-folder 04:49)
      - References on Hippocrates from National Library of Medicine 1958 October 20 (Box-folder 04:50)
      - MD magazine "Oaths" 1961 April (Box-folder 04:51)
      - National Library of Medicine Inter-Library Loan requests from C.L. Gemmill 1961 April 28 (Box-folder 04:52)
      - "The First Aphorism of Hippocrates" as published in 'Perspectives in Biology and Medicine' 1961 (Box-folder 04:53)
      - MD magazine "Oaths" 1963 November (Box-folder 04:54)
      - "Spectrum," containing articles on medical oaths 1965 (Box-folder 04:55)
      - Medical World News, containing article "Medical Ethics in a Changing World" 1966 May 20 (Box-folder 04:56)
      - Oath of Hippocrates as interpreted by UVA School of Medicine, Class of 1970 [1970] (Box-folder 04:57)
    - Manuscripts
      - "The Hippocratic Oath" partial handwritten draft n.d. (Box-folder 04:58)
      - "The Hippocratic Oath" typed draft with notations n.d. (Box-folder 04:59)
  - Greek Pharmacology
    - Letters
      - Correspondence between T.C. Skeat (Keeper of Manuscripts at the British Museum) and C.L. Gemmill 1964 September 10 - 17 (Box-folder 05:01)
      - Letter from Owsei Temkin (Editor, Bulletin of the History of Medicine) to C.L. Gemmill 1964 October 15 (Box-folder 05:02)
      - Letter from Josef-Hans Kuhn to C.L. Gemmill (German) 1964 October 23 (Box-folder 05:03)
      - Letter from Michel Janon to C.L. Gemmill (French) 1965 August 25 (Box-folder 05:04)
      - Letter from Ronald Hall (Librarian, John Rylands Library) to C.L. Gemmill 1965 October 26 (Box-folder 05:05)
      - Letters from Frank N. Egerton (Rachel McMasters Hunt Botanical Library, Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh) to C.L. Gemmill 1967 February 14-1969 June 24 (Box-folder 05:06)
      - Letter from University of Tubingen, re: a dissertation 1967 February 17 (Box-folder 05:07)
      - Letter from American Institute of the History of Pharmacy, containing references 1967 February 20 (Box-folder 05:08)
      - Letter from John B. Blake (National Library of Medicine) to C.L. Gemmill, re: references 1967 February 27 (Box-folder 05:09)
      - Letter from C.L. Gemmill to Harvard University Library, re: Hippocratic Corpus 1967 February 14 (Box-folder 05:10)
      - Correspondence between Jerry Stannard (University of Colorado, Boulder) to C.L. Gemmill, re: Hippocratic references 1967 February 14-25 (Box-folder 05:11)
      - Postcard from Orell Fussli Verlag (Publishing Company) to C.L. Gemmill, re: duplication/reprints 1969 May 5 (Box-folder 05:12)
    - Other items
      - "Pharmacy - from Library to Laboratory" by Jerry Stannard 1966 (Box-folder 05:13)
    - Manuscripts
      - "Letter of the First Century, AD of Pharmacological Interest" by C.L. Gemmill, 1 draft, 2 copies 1965 (Box-folder 05:14)
      - "Transmission of Medical Knowledge", draft n.d. (Box-folder 05:15)
  - Dunglison
    - Robley Dunglison Biographical Information n.d. (Box-folder 05:16)
    - Dunglison Family Tree n.d. (Box-folder 05:17)
    - Photograph of Robley Dunglison Portrait n.d. (Box-folder 05:18)
    - Dunglison Student Notebook
      - Letters
        - Letter from Alice Hure, re: Robley Dunglison 1964 October 19 (Box-folder 05:19)
        - Letter from D.H. Wood (University of Edinburgh) to C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1964 October 26 (Box-folder 05:20)
        - Letter to J. William Hinton from C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1964 December 17 (Box-folder 05:21)
        - From Mary Jeanne Jones to C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison's Notebook manuscript 1965 May 17 (Box-folder 05:22)
        - Letter from John E. Rasmussen (Navy Scientific Liason Officer) 1965 November 9 (Box-folder 05:23)
        - Letter from Elizabeth Adkins (Medical Librarian, Temple, Texas) to C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1965 November 8 (Box-folder 05:24)
        - Letter from Lloyd G. Stevenson (Editor, Journal of the History of Medicine) to C.L. Gemmill, re: publication of Dunglison's Notebooks 1966 July 6-August 15 (Box-folder 05:25)
        - Letter from L.M. Holloway (Curator and Cataloguer, College of Physicians of Philadelphia) to C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison Notebooks 1967 July 31 (Box-folder 05:26)
        - Letter to E. Gaskell from C.L. Gemmill, re: diabetes 1968 February 15 (Box-folder 05:27)
        - Letter from C.H. Talbot to C.L. Gemmill, re: diabetes 1968 March 27 (Box-folder 05:28)
        - Letter from Society of Apothecaries of London to C.L. Gemmill, re: medical qualification boards 1968 April 3 (Box-folder 05:29)
        - Letter from Paul Ghalioungui to C.L. Gemmill, re: diabetes and silphium 1968 July 28 (Box-folder 05:30)
      - Other items
        - "Diabetes in 1815-1816" in Gemmill's handwriting n.d. (Box-folder 05:31)
        - From folder labeled "Diabetes Dunglison" n.d. (Box-folder 05:32)
        - Edited notes on Dunglison Notebook n.d. (Box-folder 05:33)
        - Application for Research Grant-"Editing Student Notebook of Robley Dunglison, MD" draft copy, page 1 [1966] (Box-folder 05:34)
      - Manuscript
        - "The Notebook of Robley Dunglsion, Student of Clinical Medicine in Edinburgh, 1815-1816", edited draft (?) n.d. (Box-folder 05:35)
        - "The Notebook of Robley Dunglison, Student of Clinical Medicine in Edinburgh, 1815-1816" later edited draft (Xeroxed) n.d. (Box-folder 05:36)
        - "Introduction to Robley Dunglison's Clinical Notes" n.d. (Box-folder 05:37)
        - "A Tabular View of the effects of the Cold & Warm Affusions in Five Cases of Fever" n.d. (Box-folder 05:38)
    - Dunglison Bibliography
      - Miscellaneous letters and papers from Elizabeth Adkin's Dunglison Bibliography 1940 May-1962 (Box-folder 05:39)
      - Robley Dunglison Bibliography Preliminary Checklist 1951 June (Box-folder 05:40)
      - Letters
        - Correspondence between Hilda Moore (UMD Health Sciences Library) and C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1966 May 27-1968 March 30 (Box-folder 05:41)
        - Correspondence between K. Wickert and C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison dissertation, with photocopies 1966 June 3-August 8 (Box-folder 05:42)
        - Correspondence between Dorothy Hanks (History of Medicine, NLM) and C.L. Gemmill 1967 October 16-1970 January 22 (Box-folder 05:43)
        - Inquiries sent out by C.L. Gemmill regarding Dunglison 1968 February 15-28 (Box-folder 05:44)
        - Correspondence between Johns Hopkins University Medical Library and C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1968 February 20-27 (Box-folder 05:45)
        - Correspondence between Harvard Medical Library and C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1968 February 20-March 12 (Box-folder 05:46)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and The Library for the Blind (Philadelphia, PA), re: Dunglison 1968 April 26-May 1 (Box-folder 05:47)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and Library of the College of Physicians (Philadelphia, PA), re: Dunglison 1968 April 26-May 8 (Box-folder 05:48)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and Perkins School for the Blind (Watertown, Ma), re: Dunglison 1968 May 6-17 (Box-folder 05:49)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and Library of Congress Division for the Blind, re: Dunglison 1968 May 6-20 (Box-folder 05:50)
        - Correspondence with Thomas Hunter regarding grant money 1968 May 9-27 (Box-folder 05:51)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and the Royal National Institute for the Blind (London), re: Dunglison 1968 May 20-23 (Box-folder 05:52)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and American Foundation for the Blind, re: Dunglison 1968 May 20-June 18 (Box-folder 05:53)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and Harvard College Library, re: Dunglison 1968 May 20-June 12 (Box-folder 05:54)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and Overbrook School for the Blind (Philadelphia), re: Dunglison 1968 May 28-June 3 (Box-folder 05:55)
        - Letters from Samuel Radbill to C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1968 November 6-13 (Box-folder 05:56)
        - Letters from Roy P. Basler (Library of Congress) to C.L. Gemmill, re: Dunglison 1968 December 30-1969 January 7 (Box-folder 05:57)
        - Correspondence between C.L. Gemmill and the Historical Society of Pennsylvania [1968]-1969 January 2 (Box-folder 05:58)
        - Letter from Adele Matthysse (Librarian, Burndy Library, Norwalk, Connecticut), re: scientific incunabula 1969 November 26 (Box-folder 06:01)
        - Letter from the Library of the College of Physicians of Philadelphia, re: scientific incunabula 1969 December 1 (Box-folder 06:02)
      - Other items
        - Marked up list of book reviews for Dunglison n.d. (Box-folder 06:03)
        - Marked up list of reviews for Dunglison n.d. (Box-folder 06:04)
        - List of Dunglison's Clinical lectures and reports n.d. (Box-folder 06:05)
        - Application for Research Grant-Robley Dunglison Bibliography-draft copy [1967] (Box-folder 06:06)
        - Application for Research Grant-Bibliography of Robley Dunglison [1967] (Box-folder 06:07)
        - Letter from Ileen E. Stewart to C.L. Gemmill, re: grant application 1967 August 25 (Box-folder 06:08)
        - National Library of Medicine Book requests from C.L. Gemmill 1968-1970 (Box-folder 06:09)
        - Dunglison Timeline n.d. (Box-folder 06:10)
        - Dunglison Publication Timeline n.d. (Box-folder 06:11)
      - Manuscript
        - Dunglison Bibliography draft (partial) n.d. (Box-folder 06:12)
        - Dunglison Bibliography draft (partial)-History of Medicine n.d (Box-folder 06:13)
        - Dunglison Bibliography draft (partial)-Human Physiology n.d. (Box-folder 06:14)
        - Dunglison Bibliography draft (partial)-The Medical Student n.d. (Box-folder 06:15)
        - Dunglison Bibliography draft (partial)-New Remedies n.d. (Box-folder 06:16)
        - Dunglison Bibliography draft (partial)-On the Influence of Atmosphere and Locality n.d. (Box-folder 06:17)